Harvard Learning Challenged Association
哈佛学习障碍协会
And we are hosting a forum inspired by this class
受到这门课的启发 我们将举行一个论坛
entitled Learning Disabilities
名叫学习缺陷
Learning Challenges and Positive Psychology
学习障碍和积极心理学
A lot of students on campus are registered with learning disabilities
很多校内学生都有学习缺陷
and even more have learning challenges
有些甚至有学习障碍
which can include a difficulty studying or chronic procrastination
包括学习困难和长期拖延症
Also, a lot of learning disabilities
而且 很多学习障碍
are associated with higher rates of depression and low self-esteem
都与抑郁症高发率和低自尊有关
So in this forum, we hope to ask questions like
所以在这个论坛上 我们会问
"How can we think positively about learning disabilities?"
"如何积极看待学习障碍?"
And "How can we use positive psychology
"我们如何用积极心理学
to further explore this field of studying?"
进一步探索这片研究领域?"
All are welcome, whether you have learning challenge
欢迎大家参加 不管是你有学习障碍
or your friend does
还是你的朋友
or you just have a tough time studying
或者你最近遇到学习困难
or you are just interested
或者你只是感兴趣
Please come and join us
都请来参加
It's convenient time
时间很方便
one week from now, Tuesday 11:30
一周后 星期二11点半
at the Adams House Conservatory
地点是Adams宿舍音乐院
which is between the entrance and the dining hall of Adams House
就在入口和Adams宿舍的食堂中间
So mark your calendars
记住在日程表上标出来了
It should a good discussion. We hope we'll see you there
这会是一次很愉快的讨论 希望到时能见到大家
Thank you so much
非常谢谢
My name is Holly
我叫Holly
And I'm the president of an organization on campus
我是校内一个协会的主席
called the Leadership Institute at Harvard College
这个协会叫哈佛大学领导才能协会
And David and I want to just quickly mention what the club does
David和我想简单跟大家介绍一下我们的协会
One of our founders actually is one of your TFs-John Deutch
我们的一位创立人就是你们的助教John Deutch
over here helped get the group started a few years back
他几年前开始成立这个协会
So very briefly what the club has-forming programs
简单来说 我们的协会组织各种活动
all aimed up promoting leadership on campus
旨在提高校内学生的领导能力
We have a development program where we bring in speakers
我们有一个发展活动 在这个活动里 我们会请人
to work on workshops and interactive seminars
在研讨会和互动会上演讲
that help all of us on really useful skills
教会我们真正有用的技巧
like running a meeting and negotiation and public speaking
例如主持会议 谈判 公众演讲
They are all free and open to all undergraduates
这些活动对所有本科生免费开放
We also enable collaboration between student presidents
我们还会举行午餐会和论坛 让学生主席
chief editors
总编辑
captains on campus through luncheons and discussion forums
校园队长进行合作
We have an outreach program where we train Harvard undergraduates
我们还有一个拓展计划训练哈佛本科生
as instructors for leadership curriculum
当领导才能课程的讲师
And we run a one year program on Saturdays
我们有一个长达一年的活动 每周六举行
with middle school students here at Cambridge
是和我们这里的Cambridge中学生一起参加的
And lastly, we are starting a student leadership focused magazine
最后 我们正在成立一份专注于领导才能的杂志
that will be distributed in the future
在将来不久就会发行
Hey guys, My name is David Tebaldi
大家好 我叫David Tebaldi
I'm the leadership development initiative director
我是领导才能协会发展领导才能活动的
at the Leadership Institute
首要负责人
I'm here to give you a little bit of idea
我来为大家简单介绍一下
of what's in store for the fall
我们秋季会有什么活动
First of all we have the Presidents Forum
首先我们会举行主席论坛
which is a banquet that brings together the students all across the
这是一个聚集全校
students leaders from all across the campus
学生领导的宴会
to discuss their own experiences
他们会分享他们
with leadership and challenges related to that
对领导才能以及相关挑战的经验
Afterwards we had a very first magazine coming out which is pretty exciting
然后我们会出版我们第一份杂志 非常激动人心
It'll have a lot of articles about leaders that we
里面会有很多文章关于以前
hosted the past events
主持过活动的领导
and their own experience with leadership
以及他们在领导才能这方面的经验
We have a lot of other events following that as Holly mentioned before
我们接下来还会有很多活动 正如Holly刚才提到
with negotiations and a lot of public speaking events are in store
我们会有关于谈判和公众演讲的活动
If you'd like to know more
如果你们想了解更多
you can just google leadership institute at Harvard college
请搜索哈佛大学领导才能协会
and you should be able to find our website
大家就能找到我们的网页
Thank you for your time
谢谢你们
And I hope to see you at some of our events next year
希望在下一年的活动上能看到大家
So we had a breakfast this morning with the teaching staff of this class
我们今天早上和班上的助教吃了早餐
It was our final breakfast get-together
这是我们最后一次的早餐聚餐
And I'm a little bit sad
我有点伤心
So hopefully I'll be happier by the end of the class
希望上完这节课后我能开心一点
Today we'll finish up on self-esteem
今天我们会讲完自尊
and the next time is the last time we meet
下节课是我们最后一次上课
for this semester at least
至少是这个学期
And I'll summarize what we have done
我会总结一下我们讲过的内容
where we have been
我们讲过的
and all the places that we will go
和我们将要讲的内容
Just a recap on what we did
先回顾一下我们讲过的
which is on the slide now
就在幻灯片上
There's been a lot of research
有很多研究
a lot of talk of how important self-esteem is
有很多观点都说了自尊有多重要
and it is important
自尊确实很重要
There's research suggesting that it's connected to our well being
有研究表明它与我们的健康
to our success that is inversely related to crime
成功有关 低自尊通常与犯罪
substance abuse
药物滥用
unhappiness, anxiety, depression
心情低落 焦虑 抑郁有关
So self-esteem is important - we know that
所以自尊很重要 这我们知道
However, not all was well in self-esteem land
但是在自尊这个课题里 也不是天下太平的
as we discussed last time
我们上节课讲过了
Part of the problem is that there is contradictory evidence
问题之一就是自相矛盾的证据
On the one hand
一方面
self-esteem is associated with benevolence and generosity and empathy
高自尊的人通常都仁慈 慷慨和富有同情心
on the other hand
但另一方面
high self-esteem has been shown to be associated with hostility
高自尊的人又会表现出敌意
lack of cooperation, defensiveness
缺乏合作精神 有抵触情绪
There's also misunderstanding about or
另一个问题就是人们误解
about how self-esteem affects performance
自尊对表现的影响
how it affects happiness
对幸福的影响
and where that comes from
以及当中的原因
The paradox of self-esteem
自尊的矛盾
Sometimes we feel like we are doing so well
有时候我们觉得自己表现得很优秀
we are getting so many accolades
受到很多赞扬
our self-esteem increases only to go back to its base level
但自尊上升后 很快又回落到基本水平
only worse
甚至更糟
because now we have to do even more
因为我们要尽更大努力
to come back to our base level of self-esteem
才能让自尊回到基本水平
have to get more accolades
我们要得到更多的赞扬
more achievements
取得更多的成就
Nothing is enough anymore
做什么都不够了
So there are these contradictory evidence
所以有证明表明自尊的来源
where self-esteem comes from
以及它的后果
and its consequences
存在矛盾
And one of the ways to explain it is by drawing on the work
解释这些矛盾的方法之一就是借鉴别人的研究
of people like Maslow
例如Maslow
people like Nathaniel Branden
Nathaniel Branden
people like Carl Rogers, Rollo May. Lovinger
或者Carl Rogers, Rollo May Lovinger
to see how we can perhaps break down self-esteem into its components
看看我们能怎么分解自尊的基本构成
that's what my dissertation did
这就是我的论文的内容
this is what I presented to you in the previous class
也是我上节课跟大家讲的内容
basically take the ideas of the select field researchers
基本上就是讲了自尊这个领域里的研究人员的观点
who had been thinking about it
那些思考这个问题的人
people like Robert Kegan across the road from the Ed school
例如马路对面的教育学院的Robert Kegan
thinking about self-esteem more developmentally
他研究自尊的角度更倾向于发展心理学
And I presented the epigenetic model C epigenetic
我给大家介绍了那个渐成模型 渐成
once again, meaning that one level has to be fulfilled
再说一次 它的意思就是必须实现了一层
or at least partly fulfilled before we can go the next level
或者至少部分实现了一层 才能去到下一层
And the three levels are dependent self-esteem
这三层分别是依赖型自尊
independent self-esteem
独立型自尊
and unconditional self-esteem
和无条件型自尊
Dependent self-esteem - the two components of it
依赖型自尊 它有两个构成部分
first of all
首先
person with high dependence needs the accolades of others constantly
有高度依赖性自尊的人时刻需要他人的赞扬
chooses whether it's a career path or what to do this afternoon
不管是选择职业 还是决定下午做什么这样的小事
based on how much approval that will gain him or her
都是根据他人的认同来做决定的
Person with dependent self-esteem
有依赖型自尊的人
when it comes to competence
在能力感方面
always compares him or herself to others
总是拿自己跟别人比较
Am I better or am I worse? Superior or inferior?
我比他们好还是差? 比他们优秀还是不如他们?
Independent self-esteem is self-esteem that's contingent on the self
独立型自尊是一种取决于自我的自尊
in terms of how I evaluate myself
这样的人在评价自己时
that's my internal voice that's speaking
用的是自己的意见
In terms of how my levels of competence are determined
他们的能力感取决于
it depends on how much I have improved
自己认为自己进步了多少
how much better I've got
改善了多少
how much I feel that I have fulfilled my potential
觉得自己的潜力发挥了多少
That's independent self-esteem
这就是独立型自尊
not contingent on what other people say or think
并不取决于他人的言论或想法
Unconditional self-esteem is the highest level
无条件型自尊是最高层次的自尊
the level that Maslow would talk about - "the self-actualization"
也就是Maslow所说的"自我实现"
what David Schnarch talks about as "differentiated"]
David Schnarch所说的"分化良好型"
or at the level of being known rather than desiring to be validated
想被了解 而不是被认可
Unconditional self-esteem is when our self-esteem is high enough
无条件型自尊是指我们的自尊高到
we feel good enough about ourselves
让我们对自己感觉很好
not to be concerned with evaluations with others
所以我们并不在乎别人怎么看自己
or even with self evaluations
甚至不在乎自己怎么看自己
In terms of comparison
在比较方面
we don't compare; we are inter-dependent
我们不会比较 我们是相互依存的
connected to others
相互联系的
So the example that I gave last time is of a book
我上节课举的一个例子是写书
Let's say I publish a book and I have high dependent self-esteem
假设我出版一本书 我是一个高度依赖型自尊的人
First of all, I write it
首先 我写这本书
I publish it so that I can get accolades
我出版这本书 是为了得到赞扬
My primary motivation is external approval
我的首要动机是获得外界认同
My primary motivation is wanting to bring out a book
我的首要动机是想出版一本
that will be better than the other books out there
比别人的书都好的书
so relative competence as well as externally other-determined
相比较而获得的能力感 以及取决于外界
So if I bring in a book and write a book
又假设我写了一本书
and I have high independent self-esteem
我是一个高度独立型自尊的人
I write it and I evaluate it myself
我写了书 我自己评价
"this is good work, " or "this is not so good
"这是一本好书"或者"这本书不怎么样
needs improvement
需要修改"
In terms of comparison
在比较方面
I compare to myself - "I've improved a lot since I started writing
我跟自己比较 "我比起刚开始写时进步了很多
This book is actually better than my previous book
这本书比我之前一本要好
My work has become more authentic, more real. "
我的书写得更真实了"
That's independent self-esteem evaluation
这是独立型自尊的评价
Unconditional self-esteem
无条件型自尊
the highest level that we know of:
是我们所知的最高层次自尊
I write a book and I'm not concerned about evaluation
我写了一本书 我不在乎评价
whether it's good or bad - of course I want to be better and better
不管它是好是坏 我当然想变得越来越好
but that doesn't affect how I feel about myself
但这并不影响我对自己的感觉
I simply exist
我就是我
I write the book; I'm in a state of flow
我写了这本书 我处于心流状态
experiencing the experience
我体验这种经历
In terms of whether it's better than others
至于这本书是不是比别人的好
or better than I've written
或者比我以前写的好
it doesn't matter
这都不重要
What I'm happy about
我高兴的是
what makes me happy is bringing a good book into existence
我写成了一本书
And I would be as happy
如果别人也写了一本书
if someone else wrote the book
我也会同样替他感到高兴
I'd be as happy or happier that someone else wrote a better book
别人写了一本更好的书 我会同样高兴 甚至更高兴
that can help others more
这本书更能帮助到人
Important thing to understand about this model
这个模型有很重要的一点是需要明白的
the three levels is that we all have all three basically from a very young age
我们从很小的年纪开始就有这三层自尊
It's not that the Dalai Lama or Mother Teresa
并非只有达赖喇嘛或特蕾沙修女
or Nelson Mandela or Margaret Mead
曼德拉或者玛格丽特米德
that people who we know have been
这样的名人
are self-actualized
才是自我实现的人
it's not that they don't care about what other people say
他们并不是不在乎别人的看法
However, they are mostly
但他们
most of their lives, most of the time
大部分时候
self-determined - do what they believe in
都是自己决定的 做自己相信的事
feel a sense of connection to others
和他人相互联系
want to make the world a better place
想让世界变得更美好
But it's not that they don't care
但他们并非不在乎
it's not that they don't evaluate themselves relative to themselves
并非他们评价自己时不会跟自己比较
or relative to others
也不会跟他人比较
That's part of human nature
这是人的天性
My error, when I started with this research
我犯过一个错误 当我开始这个研究时
was that I said to myself
我跟自己说
"OK,I just want to have independent
"好的 我想有独立型自尊"
and later when I understood what unconditional self-esteem
当后来我明白无条件型自尊是什么时
I said, "Wel, I want to have unconditional self-esteem."
我说"我想有无条件型自尊"
And I situated those two on the good side
我把这两种自尊列为好的
and dependent self-esteem, bad
把依赖型自尊列为坏的
And what then happened?
结果呢?
It only intensified my dependency on others
只加剧了我对他人的依赖
Because when we fight nature
因为当我们有违天性时
nature fights back and we can't win
天性就会跟我们作对 我们赢不了
You know, it's like going back to the second class
就像第二节课一样
If I say to myself
如果我跟自己说
"Tal, don't be nervou, Don't be nervo, Don't be anxiou."
"Tal 别紧张 别紧张 别心急"
What happens? The pink elephants begin to come out
结果呢? 我看到粉红色大象出来了
And I become even more anxious and more nervous
我变得更焦虑更紧张了
whereas I accept it is part of my nature
但当我接受这种天性时
Let it be C permission to be human
放任它 不强求自己
It loses a lot of its vitality and force and control
它就顿时威力大减
Cause I can say
因为我可以说
"OK. Yes, I care that this person didn't like my book
"好的 这个人不喜欢我的书 我无所谓
didn't like my class
不喜欢我的课 无所谓"
And I accepted it, It's nature, It hurts me
我接受它 这是天性 我会伤心
I would much rather that they all like it
我当然想他们都喜欢
But I can move on then, and said
但转念一想 我就想通了
"OK,what would the most authentic life that I can lead?
"我要怎样做才能活出自我?
How can I the teacher who is known as opposed
我作为一个老师要怎样才能被了解
to constantly concerned about validation?"
而不是整天想着得到别人的认同?"
Active acceptance. Revisited
积极接受 回顾一下
Accepting my nature and then deciding
接受我的天性 然后决定
what would the most appropriate action to take
最合适的做法是什么
One of the, my role models is Warren Bennis
我的榜样之一是Warren Bennis
Warren Bennis has done a lot of research and a lot of speaking
Warren Bennis在领导才能这个领域
and a lot of work in the area of leadership
做过很多研究 演讲和工作
He teaches audit in University of Southern California
他先在南加州大学教旁听课
was before he was at Harvard and MIT
后来才来哈佛和麻省理工
And he came to Harvard Business School for three years
他来哈佛商学院教了三年
and the first year - as a visiting professor
第一年 作为一个客座教授
The first year I took his class
第一年我上了他的班
which was an extraordinary experience
一次非常特别的经历
The second year when he taught it
第二年他教那个班时
I was his teaching assistant
我当了他的助教
And I used to work a lot with him and interact with him
我经常和他一起工作 互动
and was constantly amazed by Warren
我经常为Warren折服
Warren, at the time was 80 years old - now he's 83
Warren当时80岁 他现在83岁了
would walk into the room and the room would light up
他走进教室时 整间教室都亮了起来
It was his smile, his posture, his openness
他的微笑 姿势 直率
his expressiveness
他丰富的表达
was there about his interacting with people
都是为了和同学发生互动
and making the other person just by being there
他的一举一动让其他人
feel better about themselves
对自己感觉更好了
And he was confident and strong
他自信坚强
and what I would classify as self-actualized as a person
我把这样的人视为自我实现的人
with very high unconditional self-esteem
他有很高的无条件自尊
And we became very close and he helped me in many areas
我们走得很近 他在很多方面都给了我帮助
most of all just by being himself - me observing him
最大的帮助就是他活出自我 我观察他
learning from him, assimilating what he had to give the world
学习他 吸收他给这个世界带来的东西
and what he was giving day in and day out
吸收他每天给数百万读他的书的人
to thousands and millions of people who have read his books
听他演讲的人
who have been to his lectures
和他有过接触的人
who've had the privilege of interacting with him
所带来的知识
And one day after a couple of years
几年后 有一天
I was his TA
我是他的助教
and we were close
我们关系很亲近
I said to him
我跟他说
"Warren, how is it that you are like this?"
"Warren 你是怎么变成现在这样的?"
How is it that you are like this?
你是怎么变成现在这样的?
And his response was put his hand on my shoulder
他的回应时 把手放在我肩膀
looked at me with his calm
看着我 带着一个平静
accepting, giving smile, and said
接受 慷慨的微笑 说
"Tal. I wasn't always like this"
"Tal 我不是一出生就这样的"
And that's where he left it
他就只说了这一句
And this is what I needed to hear
这就是我需要听到的答案
Because in his response
因为在他的回答里
where two very important - many more
有很多重要的信息
but two very important messages
而最重要的两个信息是
the first message is that it evolves
第一个 他是慢慢进步成这样的
it takes time; you don't become third level
需要时间 你不会在20岁时 或者40岁时
self-actualized individual overnight at the age of 20
一夜之间 去到第三层自尊
or even at the age of 40
变成一个自我实现的人
It takes time; it takes work; it takes self-awareness
需要时间 需要下功夫
it takes falling down and getting up
需要一次次跌倒和站起来
learning to fail
学会失败
then learning from that failure
然后从失败中学习
It takes learning to accept oneself
需要学习接受自己
it takes being open and being vulnerable and making mistakes
需要敞开心扉 接受伤害 犯错
it takes being human, fully human
需要做一个彻彻底底的人
I was not always like this
我不是一出生就这样的
The second message that I got from this
他的回答中第二个信息是
is that Warren was genuine
Warren很真诚
He was real. He didn't say to me
他很真实 他没有跟我说
"Oh Tal, stop
"Tal 别夸我
Not really. Come on. Thank you"
我也不是很厉害 过奖了"
But no
他没有这样
He was real. He knows his worth
他很真诚 他知道自己的价值
He's confident
他自信
There was no false modesty involved
他没有虚伪的谦虚
and it reminded me
这让我想起
that when I started to think about self-esteem
当我开始思考自尊时
and the true meaning of self-esteem
自尊的真正意义
as you read in Branden's work
Branden的著作中所写的意义
by the way, he and Nathaniel Branden are good friends
对了 他和Nathaniel Branden是好朋友
When I started reading Branden
当我开始读Branden的著作时
and when I realized what real self-esteem was about
当我明白真正的自尊是什么时
I realized that people with high levels of self-esteem are modest
我明白有高自尊的人都是谦虚的
You don't have the need to show off
你不需要显摆
You know, arrogance
你们知道 自大
narcissism is the exact opposite of self-esteem
自恋是自尊的对立
hubris, foolish pride is the exact opposite
目中无人 自以为是
of what a true sense of self is
跟真正意义上的自我感是完全对立的
So when I understood that
所以当我明白了这点以后
one of my important goals was to become
我的一个重要目标就是变得
more importantly to be - modest
谦虚 最重要的目标
And it was incredibly important for me
所以我越来越觉得
that everyone knows how modest I was
要让大家都知道我很谦虚
You know. Francis Bacon, the British philosopher
英国哲学家Francis Bacon说
said that modesty is but another form of ostentation
谦虚不过是换了个法子在显摆而已
And for me that certainly was the case
这句话用在我身上最合适不过了
it's not always the case
但对别人来说不总是这样
I think Warren Bennis is modest and truly modest
我认为Warren Bennis是真正的谦虚
I think Nelson Mandela
我认为曼德拉
when he is being modest, he really is modest
当他谦虚时 他是真正的谦虚
But the question is: how do you get to that level of modesty?
但问题是 你怎样才能达到那种层次的谦虚?
And you get to this level of modesty by being authentic
你要达到那种层次的谦虚 方法就是活出自我
by being real
活得真实
by going through the process
走完这个过程
And the process in many ways as we described last time
这个过程就像我们上节课说的那样
is like learning how to walk
就像学习走路
Initially when we are born
我们刚生出来时
we have no idea what walking even is
我们连走路是什么都不知道
Then later on
但慢慢地
we are able to get up
我们能站起来
but we need support either of another person
但我们需要别人扶着
or something to lean on
或者靠着什么东西
And we take our first precarious steps around a desk, for example
例如 我们靠着桌子小心地走出第一步
And after a while we can walk without help
慢慢地我们可以自己走了
But we are still thinking about every step
但我们还是要想着每一步怎么迈
and we fall down and get up again
我们跌倒了就再爬起来
learn to fail or fail to learn
学会失败 或者一错再错
And then we continue walking
然后我们继续走
and we are very conscious of how we pick up this leg
我们心里时刻想着怎么抬起这条腿
When you watch a baby learn how to walk
当你观察婴儿学走路时
it's fascinating
会觉得很神奇
So many things have come together for this simple
他们需要调动很多东西 才能完成
seemingly simple action
这么简单的一个动作
And then after a while
过了一段时间后
the baby becomes more confident
婴儿变得更自信了
And she begins to run
她开始跑了
And she no longer has to think about walking or running
她不再想着怎么走或跑
because then she naturally
因为她自然地
she simply walks
就会走了
Same with the sense of self: initially
自我感也是这样 一开始
we have no sense of self
我们没有自我感
there's no differentiation between the "me" and the mom
区分不开"我"和妈妈
or other objects in the world
或者世界上其他物件
Gradually, we develop a sense of self
慢慢地我们发展出自我感
but that sense of self is completely dependent
但这个自我感是完全依赖外界的
physically as well as psychologically
不管是身体上还是心理上
we are dependent on our parents
我们都依赖于父母
significant adults
重要的大人
older sibling
哥哥或姐姐
And then after a while
然后过了一段时间
that usually happens when we are teenagers
通常是到我们进入青春期后
we begin to assert our independence
我们开始获得独立
That's when we begin to desire
这时我们开始渴望
want to hear our own voice
听到自己的声音
want to make our own voice heard
想让别人听到自己的声音
That's the difficult teenage years
青春期这段时间很难
difficult for the teenager
对青少年来说难
difficult for the parent
对父母来说也难
But it's natural
但这是自然的
It's part of evolution
是进化的必经步骤
And we need our boundaries at that time
这时候我们需要我们的界限
And at the same time
但同时
we need to sometimes break boundaries
我们有时候又需要打破界限
We need to test reality
我们需要试探现实
Assert ourselves
确定自我
And then over time
然后随着时间过去
when we do that
如果我们这么做
over time we begin a new process simultaneously
随着时间过去 我们同时开始一个新过程
And that is the process of real differentiation
这个过程就是真正的分化
where the independent self becomes so strong
这时候独立的自我变得太强烈
that we are able to connect to others as well
我们能够和他们联系
Once again, going back to relationship
再一次 引用回讲恋爱课的内容
Nathaniel Branden: the more independent we become
Nathaniel Branden说过 我们越独立
the more interdependent we can be
我们就越互相依存
And then we evolve and that takes a long time
然后我们进步 这需要很长时间
And if we have missed out on the dependent side C for example
如果我们没有依赖的一面 例如
if we didn't get any accolades and any praise
如果我们年少时没有得到任何赞扬
and unconditional self-regard in the words of Carl Rogers
或者用Carl Rogers的话来说无条件的
when we are younger
自我关注
then we have that need - remember the model of epigeneti
我们就会有这个需求 回忆一下那个渐成模型
we can't jump over a stage
我们不能跳过一层
And very often it would take a therapist
通常我们需要一个治疗师
to provide us with unconditional self-regard
帮助我们找到无条件的自我关注
so that we can go to the next level
这样我们就能到达下一层
Or we need a relationship
或者我们需要一段关系
or relationships where we cultivate unconditional self-regard
或几段关系帮助我们培养无条件的自我关注
so that we can go to the next stage
这样我们就能到达下一层
And if we were
如果…
when we were teenagers
如果我们在青少年时期
constantly told to be quiet
不停地有人叫我们安静
to behave, prevented from asserting ourselves
守规矩 阻止我们确立自我
being ourselves
活出自我
then we are unlikely to get to the next level
那么我们就不可能顺利地
in a smooth way
到达下一层
And then very often later on in life we need to do
通常在以后的生活里 我们需要做的事就是
that first to assert ourselves
首先要确立自己
like teenagers did or do
就像青少年那样
so that we can make it to the next level
这样就能到达下一层
But regardless this is not a smooth transition
但不管怎样 这个过程不会顺顺利利
Why? Because there are no perfect parents
为什么? 因为天下没有完美的父母
because there is no perfect environment
因为天下没有完美的成长环境
there are no perfect teachers and for us to evolve naturally
没有完美的老师帮助我们自然而顺利地
and smoothly through the stages
通过这些阶段
it's just unrealistic
这是不现实的
doesn't exis, not here on earth
在地球上不存在
And then we evolve over time through the hardships
我们在艰苦中随着时间进步
through the difficulties
克服困难
making mistakes, falling
犯错 跌倒
getting up again
再爬起来
gradually the interdependent self
慢慢地独立的自我
the unconditional self-esteem emerges
无条件的自尊开始浮现
And we feel much more comfortable in our skin
我们对自己更有自信
Maslow said that he didn't find people
Maslow说他没见过
below the age of 45 who were self-actualized
有45岁以下就自我实现的人
And even those self-actualized people
即使是那些自我实现的人
still have remnants of independent
仍然有残留的一丝丝独立型自尊
as well as dependent self-esteem
和依赖型自尊
It never really goes away
这种自尊是不会彻底消失的
But it's only weaker now
但它这时变弱了
It's not dominant; it's not what they are about
它不占主导地位 这时的人不再执着于
the next accolade, the next praise
获得更多赞扬
being devastated when someone doesn't like them
当别人不喜欢他们时就伤心欲绝
being devastated when they are not the best
当自己不是最好时就伤心欲绝
They accept it. They say
他们接受了 他们会说
"O, it would be nice to win this."
"赢了固然是好 赢不了也无所谓"
And then they move on
然后他们会继续前进
And they ask
他们会问
"How can I make the world better place?
"我怎样才能让世界变得更美好?
How can I be a conduit for positive emotions?"
我怎么把积极情绪带给别人?"
Maslow didn't find anyone below the age of 45
Maslow没见过45岁以下自我实现的人
Schnarch talks about how it's in the 50s and 60s
Schnarch说要到五六十岁时
that the individuals become differentiated
人才分化
and where the highest potential for passion is within a relationship
才到酝酿出一段关系中最高层次的感情
It takes time
需要时间
I was not always this way
我不是一生下来就这样的
it was not always like this as Bennis pointed out
正如Bennis指出 不是一生下来就这样的
very important lesson
非常重要的一个道理
Many people ask about the universal nature of this theory
很多人都问这个理论是不是放之四海皆准
because you know independence is very much
因为你们知道 独立
or individualism is very much a Western construct
或者说个人主义 是西方文化
or American, West European construct
或者说美国文化 西欧文化
You know you go to Africa - very differen
如果你去非洲 这会很不同
the concept of we of a group
群体的概念
is much more central to who they are
比个体的概念更重要
You go to Asia
如果大家去亚洲
the concept of the we, collectivism
"我们"的概念 集体的概念
the group is much more central to who they are
群体的概念比个体的概念更重要
So what about other areas?
那在其他地方呢?
Is this a Western centric theory?
这是一个专属西方的理论吗?
And the answer is "not necessarily"
答案是"不一定"
You see, if our goal is to become fully actualized
如果我们的目标是完全自我实现
or to strive toward that
或者用Rogers的话来说
to be in the process of becoming a person
在成为一个人的过程中
in the words of Rogers
向着这个目标奋进
then the final
那么最后
that final stage of interdependence is same in all cultures
互相依存这个最后阶段对所有文化来说都一样
All cultures value it
所有文化都重视这一点
They value it just the same
他们同样重视这一点
the process may look different for a person in Japan
不同文化的人 这个过程可能看起来不同
and for a person in United States
日本人 美国人
for a person in Israel or Egypt
埃及人 以色列人
compared to a person living in Zimbabwe
津巴布韦人 都各不相同
The process may look different
这个过程看起来不同
However, it will have many similarities
但它有很多相同之处
Remember I talked about the Dalai Lama on the third class or so
我在第三节课时讲过达赖喇嘛
who said that one of the problems he sees in Western psychology
他说他发现西方心理的一个问题是
is that we focus too much on cultural differences
我们太着重文化差异了
And again, Dalai Lama is very
达赖喇嘛是一个
extremely sensitive culturally
文化触觉非常敏锐的人
But he says there are differences; we need to study them
他说差异确实存在 我们需要学习它们
At the same time
但与此同时
we need to study even more so the similarities
我们更需要学习相同之处
that which brings us together
正是这些相同之处把我们联合起来
that unites us
团结起来
And there are a lot of similarities
而且相同之处多不胜数
And hopefully soon there'll be more and more research
希望不久的将来会有越来越多人研究
on this topic applying it to different cultures and twigging
这个话题 并把它应用于不同的文化中
and seeing how it relates outside the Western tradition
看看它与西方文化以外的世界有什么联系
Cause most of the research that I'll mention in a minute
因为我等一下提到的大部分研究
has been done in United States
都是在美国做的
some of them in UK
有一些是在英国
Will be interesting to see what the process looks like elsewhere
如果能看看别的地方这个过程是如何的 那会很有趣
But at its core, at its core
但它的核心是
it is much more similar than different
相似多于差异
Why is it important to be independent?
为什么独立很重要?
Why is it that we should strive for this evolution?
为什么我们要奋力地达到独立阶段?
Shouldn't we stay of the conformity
为什么我们不应该遵从他人
dependence level?
依赖外界?
Now I will argue and the research
我的理由 以及很多研究结果
shows as well as historical incidents show that
还有很多历史事件都表明
it is important to cultivate independence as a way
培养独立是我们培养相互依存的
to cultivate interdependence
一个重要途径
First of all
首先
because of moral behavior
因为道德行为
if you think about the worst atrocities throughout history
如果大家想想历史上最可怕的暴行
the worst atrocities throughout history
历史上最可怕的暴行
were conducted by people conforming
正是那些遵从他人
by obedience to authority
服从权威的人犯下的
and by racist or ethnocentric beliefs and behaviors
那些种族主义或民族主义的信念和行为导致的
Now look at these three things that I just
现在来看看我刚才提到的三件事
obedience to authority - a person
服从权威 一个人
with high dependence self-esteem
如果有很高的依赖性自尊
is much more likely to be obedient
就越有可能服从
to an authority figure
权威人物
Why? Because he or she seeks accolades
为什么? 因为这样的人寻求赞扬
they seek approval
他们寻求认同
They don't feel strong enough themselves
他们没有强烈的自我感
They need that very charismatic leader to tell them
他们需要一个有魅力的领袖告诉他们
"Oh,you are fine, You are OK, You are superior"
"你真棒 你真厉害 你太了不起了"
Because that's where their sense of self is dependent on
因为他们的自我感依赖于这些赞扬
because we are much more likely to conform to what a group is doing
如果我们需要不停地获得群体的赞扬
if we need constantly the accolades of that group
我们就更可能遵循群体的做法
You think about the Milgram experiment
大家想想Milgram的实验
you think about Asch experiments
Asch的实验
those of you who've taken Psych 15,or Psych 1
上过第15节和第1节的同学
You think about racism. What is racism?
大家想想种族主义 什么是种族主义?
Racism is about comparison and wanting to assert superiority
种族主义就是通过比较一些外在因素
on the base of some external factor
来证明自己高人一等
In other words
换言之
I'm not good enough as I am
我本身不够好
You know, to prove how good I am
证明不了我有多好
I have to compare myself to another
我必须拿自己跟别人比较
whether I choose you know, place of residence
我可以比较居住的地方
whether I choose upbringing
比较成长教育
whether I choose the color of the skin
比较肤色
It's about relative competence
它的中心是相对能力感
Whereas people who are independent
但是独立的人
don't have the need or have less of that need for comparison
没有这种比较的需求 或者说这种需求没那么强烈
as well as less of that need to conform
遵循他人的需求也没那么强烈
They are true to principles
他们坚持原则
their own principles
他们自己的原则
Now this is not a panacea
但原则并不是万灵药
This is not always good
原则并不总是好的
because I'm sure there are also Nazis
因为纳粹分子
who are true to their principles
也很坚持自己的原则
But as I'll show later in research
但我等一下讲的研究
those who are true to their principles are more likely
表明坚持原则的人更可能
to follow their heart
听从自己的心
And unless their heart is damaged
只要他们的心没有受伤
I mean that in a true sense of the word, damaged
我说的受伤不是一个比喻
they will seek to do good
他们会追求做好事
They will seek to help
他们会追求帮助他人
Their levels of empathy will increase
他们的移情会增加
And this is the paradox of empathy
这是移情的矛盾
It's actually when we cultivate empathy
当我培养移情时
or rather when we cultivate
或者说当我们培养…
for lack of a better term
实在找不到更好的词
and I actually don't want to use a new term
我也不想用一个新词
When we cultivate self-love
当我们培养自爱时
when we cultivate self-esteem
当我们培养自尊时
that's when we are most likely
我们就会更有可能变得
to be empathic and to love others
富有同情心 爱别人
Look at the golden rule
大家想想黄金原则
love your neighbors as you love yourself
要像爱自己一样爱你的邻居
What does that
在这个原则里
what is the prerequisite of loving your neighbor?
爱你的邻居的先决条件是什么?
The self
爱自己
You are the standard
你就是标准
we are the standard of how we evaluate others
我们自己是我们评价他人的标准
because our behavior toward others very often
因为我们怎么对待他们经常…
not always
不是通常
very often - mirrors our behavior toward ourselves
但经常都反映了我们怎么对待自己
So people cultivating independent sense of self
所以那些培养独立自我感的人
who have a strong self identity are better able to identify with others
那些有强烈自我认同的人 更能认同别人
In addition to moral behavior
除了道德行为以外
better cognitive performance - you see
还会有更好的认知表现
people who have a strong dependent self-esteem
有强烈依赖型自尊的人
or are primarily driven by what other people say
或者说行动主要由他人言论决定的人
will follow the rule that has already been taken
会遵循别人在遵循的规矩
They will, can potentially be great mechanics
他们很可能变得就像一台机器一样
because they'll work hard for these accolade
因为他们会为了得到赞扬而努力
and that's a good thing, to work hard
努力是好事
But they'll basically remain within the box
但他们不会打破陈规
whereas the people who have a stronger sense of independent self-esteem
而有强烈独立型自尊的人
think outside the box
就会打破陈规
choose the path that hasn't already been taken
选择别人没有走过的道路
That doesn't mean that they can't walk in the pat
但这并不代表他们不会选择
that has been taken
别人已经走过的路
if that is what they really
只是这是他们真正
really want to do with their lives
真正想要的生活就行了
So you know it's just as much sign of dependence when we say
所以如果我们说"别人说走东 我偏偏走西"
"Wel,I am gonna do the opposite of what everyone else does."
这同样也是依赖型的
because I'm still dependent on what everyone else does
因为我的行为还是取决于他人
So that's not independent self-esteem
所以这不是独立型自尊
That's just more dependence
而是依赖型自尊
But if I sit down and I say
如果我坐下说
"Ok, what do I really, really want to do with my life?"
"好的 我该怎么过我的人生?"
And I think about it truly
我很认真地想
Put myself in a world that no one would know what I was doing
把自己置身于一个没人知道我在做什么的世界
I'm much more likely to identify that thing which is my passion
我会更可能找到我的爱好
my core, my calling - be it in investment banking
我的核心 我的使命 也许是在投资银行工作
or work in the UniLu
也许是在UniLu工作
It doesn't matter
这并不重要
The question is "What is the source of that"
问题是"我的动力是什么?"
Person with independent self-esteem is committed to continuous learning
有独立型自尊的人活到老学到老
Remember the John Carlton's study C what differentiated the HBS grads
回忆一下John Carlton的研究 在哈佛商学院的毕业生中
the extraordinary ones from the rest
优等生与别的学生之间的区别就是
was that, they were always asking questions
他们总是问问题
They always wanted to learn more
他们总是想学更多
They didn't get out of C you know
他们不会
graduate from college or graduate from business school
从大学或商学院毕业后
or from a PHD program
或者读完博士
or wherever it is, and say
诸如此类的学位后 说
"OK,I know enough"
"我懂得够多了"
Or "Now I'm a manager; now I'm the leader
"现在我是经理了 现在我是领导了
I'll tell people how they should…
我会告诉人们应该做什么"
This is the amazing thing about Warren Bennis
这是Warren Bennis的一个优点
He's always asking questions
他总是问问题
He's always interested in what people are doing
他对别人做的事感兴趣
He's always learning
他总是在学习
Happiness, levels of happiness are higher
我等一下会给大家看一个研究
and I'll show you the research in a minute
当我们有独立型自尊时
when we experience a sense of independent self-esteem
我们的幸福感会更高
We are much calmer when we don't constantly
我们会更平静 我们不会不停地
have to prove ourselves to others
向别人证明自己
It is enervating to constantly be on the guard
总是处于警惕状态是一件很劳心劳力的事
Is this person gonna like me? How do I gain their validation?
这个人会喜欢我吗? 我怎么得到他们的认同?
We are much calmer when we say
当我们这样想时 我们会更平静:
"Let me express myself
"让我表达自己
And yes it may hurt me
没错 我也许会受伤害
It will hurt me, if they don't like me
如果他们不喜欢我 我会伤心
That's OK. I'm resilient
没问题 我承受得住
I'm strong, I can deal."
我很坚强 我可以接受"
Much calmer - sense of being
存在感更平静了
when we express rather than constantly try to impress
当我们表达自己 而不是时刻想着表现自己
Imagine how much lighter our lives can be
想象一下我们的生活会变得多轻松
if, when we are here
如果 当我们在教室时
or when we walk out of here
或者当我们走出教室时
we experience the sense of being
我们感受到这种存在感
more and more of the time
越来越多地…
again, not perfectly
重申一次 不是完全地
because that's not human
因为这有违人的天性
but more and more of the time to just be, to exist
但我们可以越来越多地单纯地存在
to celebrate our existence and the existence as a whole
感激我们的存在 作为一个整体存在
Let me share with you just some of the research
我给大家讲几个研究
There hasn't been a lot
这样的研究不是很多
And I wanna share with you just some of the work that I did for
我想给大家讲我做的一些研究
as part of my PHD and a little bit beyond
是我读博士学位时做的 后来还继续做了一点
The first research that was really able to deal with
第一个研究是关于
the paradox of self-esteem
自尊的矛盾
of how some people get so much accolade
也就是说 有些人得到很多赞扬
and yet their self-esteem decreases
但他们的自尊下降了
or how some people have high self-esteem or hostile
而那些有很高自尊的人 有些有敌对情绪
versus others that are generous and benevolent
但有些却对别人宽厚仁慈
The first research that was done was by Kernis
第一个研究是Kernis做的
who back in 1995 came up with the concept of self-esteem stability
他在1995年提出自尊稳定性这个概念
And he said what actually can predict
他说 真正能够预测
whether a person will be hostile or generous
一个人究竟是敌对还是宽厚
whether their self-esteem over time will be high
他们的自尊会随着时间增高
or whether it will lower over time is not a self-esteem per se
还是降低的 不是自尊本身
but rather is the stability of their self-esteem
而是自尊的稳定性
And what he showed - he followed people
他发现…他追踪实验对象
you know, for example, for a week or two weeks
例如 一两周
and he would measure their state rather than trait
他会测评他们的状态自尊而不是特质自尊
their state self-esteem at the time
他们当时的状态自尊
So there were certain people who
有些人…
if this is the self-esteem level
假设这里是自尊水平
and this is time
这里是时间
There were people whose self-esteem at this point
在某个时候 有些人的自尊在这里
was here and then the next day
然后第二天
here, and then here
在这里 然后这里
and then here again, and then here
然后又回到这里 这里
and here and here
这里…
and he measured, let's sa, ten times
假设他测了十次
And what he wanted to see
他想测出
to measure - the standard deviation of the spread
这些数据分布的标准偏差
How close was it? How stable was it?
它有多接近? 有多稳定?
So this would be someone with
假设这个人
maybe on average
平均来说
high self-esteem
有很高的自尊
but with a lot of fluctuations
但有很多起伏
Other people were more like this
有些人则像这样
Again, ups and downs
也有起起伏伏
but sometimes large fluctuations
有时是很大的起伏
but overall
但总体来说
pretty stable
很稳定
Same level of self-esteem
同样水平的自尊
trait self-esteem
特质自尊
but state self-esteem fluctuated far less
但状态自尊的起伏少了很多
And what he showed was that it was the stability
他发现 是自尊的稳定性
rather than self-esteem per se that determined
而不是自尊本身 决定了
whether or not a person would be hostile or benevolent
一个人是敌对还是仁慈
People with unstable self-esteem
自尊不稳定的人
were more likely to be hostile
更可能充满敌对情绪
People with more stable self-esteem
而自尊更稳定的人
were more likely to be generous and benevolent
更可能宽厚仁慈
resolving a lot of the contradictions
这就解释了自尊理论的
misunderstanding in the literature
很多矛盾和误解
When I saw this, I had a eureka
当我看到这个理论时 我顿悟了
personal eureka experience
亲身体验到的一次顿悟
And I said
我说
"This is it! He's onto something."
"就是它了 他找到答案了"
And what I did in my master's thesis back in 2000
我在2000年写我的硕士论文时
was created a questionnaire
我设计了一个问卷
a very simple questionnaire that measured dependent versus
一个很简单的问卷 测量依赖型自尊
independent self-esteem
和独立型自尊的对比
And I measured students
我测评学生
mostly Harvard students - I did also cross sectional in Singapore
大部分是哈佛学生 我还在新加坡做了代表性抽样调查
I was spending a lot of time there at the time - similar results
我那时经常在新加坡 得出同样的结果
Asia and here
亚洲和美国的一样
at least in Singapore and in United States
至少新加坡和美国的一样
And what I found was that dependent self-esteem
我发现 依赖型自尊
was associated with instability
与不稳定性有关
independent self-esteem was associated with stability
而独立型自尊与稳定性有关
In other words
换言之
I came up with one measure that instead measuring ten times
我只测量了一次 而不是十次
whether that kind of self-esteem would lead to hostility
到底这种自尊会导致敌对情绪
anxiety, versus calmness or generosity
焦虑 还是平静或宽厚
I used just one measure
我只用了一个测量数据
And that's what I found
我发现
very high correlation between dependent self-esteem
依赖性自尊与自尊不稳定性
and self-esteem instability
高度相关
positive correlation
两者成正比
and a positive correlation between independent self-esteem
而独立型自尊和自尊稳定性
and self-esteem stability
也成正比
Then some of my students at the time did research on it
当时我的一些学生也就此做了一些研究
For example, Mellisa Christino
例如 Mellisa Christino
who you'll meet
你们会在这门课上
at least some of her writing later on in this class
看到她写的一些东西
did her senior thesis as an undergrad here
她本科时写的毕业论文
on showing the connection between independent self-esteem and happiness
就是表明独立型自尊和快乐
and independent self-esteem and flow
独立型自尊与心流的关系
Those who had high independent self-esteem
那些有高度独立型自尊的人
were most likely to experience flow on athletic field
最有可能在运动场上体验到心流
which is where her research was - Harvard athletics
因为这就是她的研究对象 哈佛运动员
also connected to higher levels of happiness
高度独立自尊的人也有更高的幸福感
Then my dissertation was trying to pin down these exact characteristics
我的论文是想准确地找出
that were problematic in self-esteem literature
自尊理论存在的问题
Remember, high self-esteem means narcissism
我说过 高度自尊意味着自恋
How do you differentiate?
怎么区分这两者?
Well, what I found in the dissertation was that
我在论文里发现
narcissism is connected actually to high dependent self-esteem
自恋其实是与高度依赖型自尊有关
There was no correlation between independent self-esteem and narcissism
而自恋与独立型自尊没有什么关系
When it comes to generosity
至于宽厚
this was probably the most surprising result of the study
这也许是研究中最令人意外的结果
people with independent self-esteem
有独立型自尊的人
were actually more generous and benevolent
其实更宽厚仁兹
both in terms of self report and in terms of their actual behavior
不仅自我报告如此 对他人的行为也是如此
toward other people - a strong sense of self
非常强烈的自我感
Remember, love your neighbor as you love yourself
我说过 像爱自己一样爱你的邻居
Do not do unto others which you would not have done to yourself
己所不欲 勿施于人
And when you have a high standard for the self
当你对自我有一个高标准时
there is a high standard for the other
对他人也会有一个高标准
And that usually happens automatically
通常这是无意识地发生的
because we mirror our behavior toward the "I"
因为我们怎么对待他人就会怎么对待自己
And then hostility
还有敌对情绪
no correlation between hostility and self-esteem per se
敌对情绪与自尊本身没有关系
because some people have
因为有些
with high self-esteem, have high levels of hostility
有高度自尊的人 有很高的敌对情绪
some people with high self-esteem have low levels of hostility
但有些有高度自尊的人 敌对情绪很低
and more generosity
而且更宽厚仁慈
But dependent and independent self-esteem predicted hostility
但依赖型和独立型自尊能预测敌对情绪
Those with high self-esteem that was mostly dependent
那些有高度自尊的人 而且自尊主要是依赖型的
were more likely, not always, not every person
这样的人更可能…但也有例外 不是所有人都会这样
but on average, were more likely to display hostility
但平均来说 这样的人更可能表现出敌对
those people with high self-esteem that is mostly independent
而那些有高度自尊 而且主要是独立型自尊的人
were much more open, cooperative and generous
会更坦率 合作 宽厚
Perfectionism - two of my students at that time
完美主义 那时我有两个学生
Tiffany Ignaczyk and Kate Richey
Tiffany Ignaczyk和Kate Richey
who is a TF in this class
她是这个班的助教
did fantastic work showing the connection between perfectionism
做了一个很优秀的研究 表明完美主义
and self-esteem - how people with high independent self-esteem
和自尊的关系 有高度独立型自尊的人
were less likely to be perfectionistic
他们是完美主义者的可能性更低
Why? Because it is about self expression
为什么? 独立型自尊的人更注重表达自己
it's about constantly learning and growing
注重学习和成长
And part of learning and growing
而学习和成长
is falling down and getting up again
就必定要跌倒再爬起
no other way to learn
学习只有这个途径
Whereas dependent self-esteem were more concerned
而依赖型自尊更注重…
the words of Mihnea Moldoveanu that I quoted last time
我上节课引用Mihnea Moldoveanu说的话
we say we want the truth
我们声称自己想要真相
what we mean is that we want to be correct
但其实我们只是想自己是正确的
more dependent on how they perceived
更依赖于他人的看法
more perfectionistic, more afraid of failure
更完美主义 更害怕失败
So this applies also - and we talked about before
这同样适用于…我们之前讲过
but I just want to point it out again - to relationships
但我想再说一次 适用于恋爱
That's work on the topic
这也是David Schnarch
David Schnarch again where we talked about
就这个课题所做的研究 我们说过
how do we get to the stage of being known
我们怎么达到被了解的阶段
rather than being validated
而不是被认可的阶段
And that doesn't mean that at the age of 70 or 80
这并不代表在七八十岁时
when we are fully evolved
当我们完全进化了
we don't enjoy or need at times the validation of our partner
我们并不喜欢 或者不需要我们伴侣的认可
We do
我们需要
But at the same time
但同时
we are much more about self expression
我们更关心的是表达自我
Here is what David Schnarch has to say
David Schnarch是这样说的
"Differentiation is your ability to maintain your sense of self
"分化是你维持自我感的能力
when you are emotionally and/or physically
当你情绪上和/或身体上
close to others
与别人亲近
especially as they become increasingly important to you
尤其是这些人变得对你越来越重要时
Differentiation permits you to maintain your own course
分化使你维持自己的道路
when lovers, friends
当爱人 朋友
and family pressure you to agree and conform
家庭向你施压 让你同意和遵从时
Well-differentiated people can agree without feeling
分化良好的人能够同意 但又不会觉得
like they're 'losing themselvs'
他们"失去自我"
and can disagree without feeling alienated and embittered."
能够不同意 但又不会觉得被排挤和难受"
This is what being known is all about
这正是被了解的含义
being yourself, being differentiated
做你自己 分化出来
This is what independent self-esteem is
这就是独立型自尊的核心
this is what ultimately interdependence
这是最高境界的相互依存的
is all about
真谛
easier said than done
说来容易做来难
But again it's very helpful to have that as a heuristic
但用它来启发我们是非常有用的
the back of your mind
在我们潜意识里
to notice that it's happening
当它发生时 能够注意到
Because at the age of 20
因为在20岁这个年龄
you are also experiencing moments of interdependence
你们也会经历相互依存的时刻
real connection with a friend, family
与朋友家人产生真正的联系
just walking in the yard and admiring the beauty of it all
走在后院里 欣赏美景
and  these are precious moments that over time
这些珍贵的时刻 随着时间过去
we can have more and more of
我们会有越来越多
if we follow the natural path
只要我们跟从这条自然的道路
the natural evolution
自然的发展
Going back to the analogy of walking
继续用回走路那个比喻
I'm very often when - we know these you know
我经常…我们知道
stories through history
历史上有很多故事
people were put in you know shoes
有些人被迫穿上
that were too small for them or were not allowed to try and walk
太小的鞋子 或者被剥夺走路的自由
such as very often the case was in Romanian under Ceausescu
Ceausescu统治下的罗马尼亚就是这样
where people were not allowed to develop naturally
人们无法自然发展
when our natural development is hindered
当我们的自然发展被阻碍了
and it can be hindered
这是有可能的
we don't evolve as we can
我们就不能如我们所能的那样发展
So the question is also on the psychological level
所以在心理层面上也有这个问题
how can we evolve as we can? And some of the tools
我们怎样才能如我们所能地发展? 你们在这个学期
that you learned throughout the semester
所学到的一些方法
whether it is the cognitive tool of learning
不管是认知的学习方法
the permission to be human
允许自己有人的天性
or the tools that you can actually apply
还是你们具体地运用的方法
such as keeping a journal
例如写日记
such as exercising
做运动
such as doing the gratitude exercise
学会感恩
such as meditating, or doing yoga
冥想 练瑜伽
All these things as you'll see are ways
这些方法都是
of becoming more self-actualized
有助实现自我的方法
of expediting the process
它们能加速这个过程
And when we expedite the process
当我们加速这个过程
it means that right now right here we are able to experience
就意味着此时此刻我们就能越来越多地
that sense of being much more often
体验到那种存在感
we don't need to wait until we are 50 or 60 or 70
我们不用等到50 60或70岁
We can on that healthy journey way before that
我们可以早早地就踏上那条健康的道路
So how do we do it? How do we do it?
那么我们该怎么做?
Let me go back to the model
我们说回
we talked about when we discussed change
我们讲改变时讲过的那个模型
And we talked about the ABC of change
我们讲过改变的ABC
Affect. Behavior, and Cognition
A是情感 B是行为 C是认知
And I mentioned that the most important approach to change
我说过改变的最重要方法
the most effective approach to change is the B, the Behavior
改变的最有效方法是B 行为
And I introduced this model of how attitudes change behavior
我用一个模型讲过态度如何改变行为
and in turn how behavior changes attitudes
反过来行为如何改变态度
Remember self-perception theory
大家回忆一下自我知觉理论
if you want to improve in one area in our lives
如果你想在某个生活领域得到改善
the best thing to do is to behave as we would
最好的方法就是让自己的行为变得像改善了一样
If I want high self-esteem
如果我想要高度自尊
I need to behave like a person with high self-esteem behaves
我的行为就要像一个有高度自尊的人
Why? Because self-esteem is simply an attitude
为什么? 因为自尊就是一种态度
it's the attitude I have toward the self
是我对自我的态度
it's the I evaluating the me
是我对自己的评价
And to enhance that attitude
要提高这种态度
I need to engage - or the most effective way
我就要…或者说最有效的办法
not the only way
不是唯一的办法
but the most effective way is to engage in behavior of a person
最有效的办法 就是表现出一个
with high self-esteem
有高度自尊的人的行为
which is why it's so important to have role models
所以榜样的作用很重要
And I'm saying that in plural
我说的榜样不止一个
It's important to have role models
有榜样很重要
people we can look up to
我们可以学习这些人
and say
说
"I want to have that chara...
"我想有这样的性格…
No. I want to have the calm and the acceptance
不 我想有Warren Bennis那样的
and the generosity of spirit that Warren Bennis has
平静 包容和慷慨精神
I want to have the passion
我想有Marva Collins身上的
for teaching that Marva Collins displays
那种对教学的热爱
integrate that aggregates of role models
把榜样的所有优点综合起来
so that we can behave and over time achieve that attitude
这样我们就能有他们那样的行为 并且慢慢地培养
that we are looking for
我们追求的那种态度
So let me go over a few of them of how to enhance self-esteem
我来讲一下提高自尊的几个方法
We've discussed most
大部分都已经讲过了
so this is a good summary of some of the things that we went through
所以这也算是很好地总结一下我们讲过的内容
First, people with high independent self-esteem generally
首先有高度独立型自尊的人通常…
as we saw before from the research
正如我们之前从研究中看到的那样
Melissa Christino's research and others'
包括Melissa Christino和其他人的研究
are generally calmer
他们通常更平静
So independent self-esteem is the attitude
所以独立型自尊是一种态度
calm is the behavior
平静是一种行为
which also means that people who behave calmly
也就是说 行为平静的人
will increase over time their independent self-esteem
他们的独立型自尊会随着时间增加
And we see that in related research on meditation for example
我们在和冥想相关的研究中看过 例如
on mindfulness
正念冥想
as we induce more of it
当我们越来越多地练习这种方法
our self-esteem
我们的自尊
and it is the independent part of self-esteem
我们独立型的自尊
because they are not about accolades
因为它不需要赞扬
"Oh I meditated so well today
"我今天冥想得真好
Everyone, clap."
大家给我鼓掌"
It's not about that
这不是这种自尊的重点
It's about inducing calm
它的重点是带来平静
being centered, being myself
关注自己 活出自己
Or physical exercise
又例如运动
physical exercise induces calm
运动能带来平静
because it releases certain enzyme
因为它在体内释放某种酶
certain chemicals in the body so that over time
某些化学物质 这样随着时间过去
it actually strengthens our independent self-esteem indirectly
它能直接增强我们的独立型自尊
because behavior
因为行为
experiencing the calm leads to a changing attitude
体验了平静 导致态度的转变
Imagine that a spell of anonymity has been cast on you
假设你中了一个无名咒语
From now on and for the rest of your life
从现在起在你的余生里
no one will know what you are doing
没有人会知道你做什么
no one but you will know how good you are
除了你自己 没有人知道你有多好
how generous you are
你有多宽厚
how benevolent you are
你有多仁慈
No one but you will know how wealthy and powerful
除了你自己 没有人知道你有多富有多强大
and important you are
你有多重要
You and you alone will know about all your accomplishments
只有你自己知道你的成就
you and you alone will know about how ethical
只有你知道你有多好的操守
moral and wonderful you are
道德和性格
In such a world where a spell of anonymity has been cast on you
在这样的一个世界里 你中了无名咒语
what would you do?
你会怎么做？
Familiar, anyone? What would you do?
有谁觉得很熟悉吗? 你们会怎么做?
Now as I mentioned in the response paper
正如我在课后作业里提过那样
this does not mean that this is what I need to do
这并不代表我们在匿名世界里怎么生活
with my life - what I would do in this anonymous world
在现实世界里就应该怎么生活
What it is saying though is in such world
这个方法的意义是 在这样一个世界里
or doing this exercise
或者说做这样的练习
it can help us hone in
它能磨练我们
on what we would do regardless of the accolades
在抛开赞扬和声望的情况下
and praise and prestige
我们会怎么做
I do this exercise regularly - as you know
我经常练习这个方法 大家知道
no exercise in this class that I assign to you is foreign to me
在这个班上 我介绍给大家的方法 我都一一练过
I do them all
我都练过
I'm going through this class just as you are
我也像大家一样边上课边学习
And I do this class, this regularly
我会经常用这个方法
And for example, when I did it as a graduate student here
例如 我在这里读研究生的时候
my response was that in such a world
我当时的答案是在那样的一个世界里
I actually would not get a PHD
我可能连博士学位都拿不到
I would not get a PHD
我不会拿到博士学位
because it wasn't that pleasurable to me - very meaningful
因为读博对我来说不是一件很愉快的事 虽然很有意义
but less pleasurable to me
但没那么愉快
I wasn't that good at it
我读得不是很好
didn't feel like I was thriving
不觉得我自己有什么惊人能力
But I also said to myself that in our world
但我也跟自己说 在现实世界里
not in that world where no one would know what I was doing
不是那个没人知道我在做什么的世界
but in a world where people know what I'm doing
而是在一个别人知道我在做什么的世界
I would need a PHD in order to teach at a university
我需要一个博士学位才能在大学任教
which is why I continued and eventually got my PHD
所以我继续学习 最终拿到了我的博士学位
I did this exercise just before I graduated
我是在毕业前不久做这个练习的
And I was thinking about different areas to pursue
我当时在考虑不同的出路
And I said, what would I do in such a world
我想 在一个没有人知道我在做什么的世界里
where no one would know what I was doing?
我会做什么?
And the answer to that was I would teach
我的答案是教书
The answer to that was I would not do research
我的答案是我不会做研究
That was very clear
这是很肯定的
And that's when I decided to get out of the tenure track option
所以那时候我决定放弃争取终身任期
even though there was a lot of pressure on me from the outside
即使当时外界 那些关心我的人
from people who cared about me
给了我很大的压力
And they said "Look, two or three articles
他们说"再写两三篇文章
and you'll get into a great place, and the tenure track
你就能拿到一个很好的职位 争取终身任期
You can do it. You know your PHD, can be published."
你能做到的 你的博士论文可以发表的"
But I knew that wasn't the life that I wanted to lead
但我知道我不想过那样的生活
Is there a price for it? Yes
我要为此付出代价吗? 要
I mean one of the price is that, you know
其中一个代价就是
this is my second last class at Harvard
这是我在哈佛的倒数第二节课了
But what kind of world
但我想要什么样的世界
what kind of life did I want for myself
我想过什么样的生活
And that exercise helped me hone on that
这个方法帮助我找到了
What are your passions? What you really
你热爱什么? 你真正
really want to do with your life?
想过的是怎么样的人生?
Where do you see yourself 10 years from now
你希望10年 20年后
or 20 years from now?
你会变成什么样?
What's really important for you?
什么对你来说是非常重要的?
What's important for you
什么对你来说是重要的
that you would do regardless of other people's approval
就算没有别人的认同 点头 赞扬和欢呼
nods, accolades or cheering
反对或批评
or disapproval, or criticism?
你也会做的?
What would you do in such a world?
你在这样一个世界里会做什么?
It's an important question to ask
这是一个很重要的问题
People who experience
那些…
who have high independent self-esteem pursue their passions
有高度独立型自尊的人会追求他们的兴趣
people who pursue their passions enjoy higher levels of self-esteem
那些追求他们兴趣的人会有更高的自尊
People who enjoy a lot of flow
那些有很多心流的人
their independent self-esteem will increase as well
他们的独立型自尊也会增加
Ask yourself: where do you experience flow?
问问你自己 "你什么情况下体验过心流?
Where do you lose yourself? Is it when you read?
你什么时候忘我过? 是你读书的时候吗?
Is it over dinner
是坐在
when you are sitting next to your block mates?
你队友旁边吃晚餐时吗?
Is it when you write?
是你写作时吗?
Is it when you are standing in front of a class
是你站在全班同学前面
speak in an after school program?
介绍一个课后活动时吗?
When do you experience it?
你什么时候体验过?
When did you experience it in the past? Ask yourself
你以前什么时候感受过心流? 问问你自己
Because that very often is the best predictor of future flow
因为它最能预测到你未来什么情况下会有心流
What kind of life do you want to lead?
你想过什么样的人生?
What do you really, really want to do?
你真正想做的是什么?
People with high independent self-esteem put themselves on the line
有高度独立型自尊的人会付诸行动
They cope, they stretch themselves constantly
他们会应对 不停地加强自己
Because they are always about learning and growing
因为他们总是想学习成长
improving making more of difference
进步 发挥更大的作用
touching more people
触及更多的人
And people who cope
那些应对的人…
remember, self perception theory
大家回忆一下 自我知觉理论
people who cope over time
那些应对的人 随着时间过去
will enjoy higher levels of independent self-esteem
会获得更高的独立型自尊
Even if they fall while doing it
即使他们这样做的时候跌倒过
even if she says no four times
即使失败了四次
they get up again and they get stronger
他们会重新站起来 变得更强大
And their independent self-esteem strengthens over time
他们的独立型自尊会随着时间增强
The graph doesn't look just like this
那个图并不是这样子的
the ups and downs with spikes
起起伏伏 有高有低
It looks with same ups and downs
真正的图是有起有伏
but with an upward trajectory of well being
但健康 快乐和自尊的走势
happiness and self-esteem
是呈上升趋势的
Humble behavior - genuine humble behavior
谦虚 真诚的谦虚
One of my favorite texts
我最喜欢的一本书
and I think one of the most important texts in my tradition
也是我的文化里最重要的一本书之一
Pirkei Avos, the Chapter of the Fathers
Pirkei Avos 《先贤箴言》
There's a sentence there
里面有一句话
a proverb  that I've been reading over and over and over again
一句谚语 我读了一遍又一遍
and never could understand
但一直都参透不了
until I heard an interpretation of a well-known Rabbi
直到我听到一个著名的拉比
Rabbi Mitchell Wohlberg about this interpretation
拉比Mitchell Wohlberg 他对句话的解释
And here is the sentence
这句话是这样说的
I'm translating: those who chase after honor
我翻译过来:那些追逐荣誉的人
honor will run away from them
荣誉会躲避他们
those who run away from honor
那些躲避荣誉的人
honor will chase them
荣誉会追逐他们
Let me repeat: those who run after
再说一次:那些追…
who chase honor
追逐荣誉的人
honor will run away from them
荣誉会躲避他们
those who run away from honor
那些躲避荣誉的人
honor will chase them
荣誉会追逐他们
And it didn't make sense to me until I put it in the context
我一直都参透不了 直到我听到拉比Wohlberg
the result of the lecture by Rabbi Wohlberg of self eteem
关于自尊的一场演讲 并把它跟这句话结合起来理解
Honor is essentially honoring the self
荣誉的本质是尊敬自己
believing in one self
相信自己
And if I'm constantly about chasing honor
如果我不停地追逐荣誉
the next accolade, the next prize
追逐下一个赞扬 下一个奖
the next approval, the next validation
下一个认同 下一个认可
then honor will run away from me
荣誉就会躲避我
And then I'll have to push that stone up steeper
下一次我就要在更陡的山坡上
incline the next time
把石头推上去
And I continue to chase that honor and I get there
我继续追逐荣誉 等我到达了山顶
and then the rock rolls back down again
石头又会滚下来
And Sisyphus continues on and on with the steep becoming...
科林斯王就要继续推石头 而山坡变得
with the incline becoming steeper
越来越陡峭
Whereas if I run away from honor - behave humbly
相反 如果我躲避荣誉 言行谦虚
over time honor, true honor
随着时间过去 真正的荣誉
internally generated honor will chase me
打心底发出的荣誉感就会追逐我
Behavior can change attitude
行为可以改变态度
It takes time
这需要时间
And again at the beginning
重申 一开始
as I mentioned to you before
正如我之前说过
I wanted to be modest and I wanted everyone to know
我想变得谦虚 我想大家都知道
how modest I was and how humble I was
我有多谦虚
And I understood that well
我明白
that's not genuine
那不是真诚的谦虚
but I can still behave and act in a humble way
但我仍然可以保持谦虚的言行
And over time
随着时间过去
it becomes more and more part of who we are
它就会慢慢地融入我们
Behavior changing attitude doesn't happen overnight
行为不会一夜之间就改变态度
And again it doesn't mean that a person at 80
但这并不意味着一个80岁
who is evolved and actualized does not look for honor at all
完成进化 实现自我的人 不会追寻荣誉
does not feel good when he or she is praised
当他们被赞扬时 不会觉得高兴
That's natural - part of who we are
那是很自然的 是人的天性
This is an important one
以下这个知识点很重要
We've talked about it a lot in the class about simplifying
我们在班上经常讲简化生活
The...
那…
I've often wondered the why is it that in a county
我经常想 为什么在一个
like the United States
像美国这样的国家里
such an individualistic country - self-reliance
一个追崇个人主义 自为更生的国家
most of you read it in high school by Emerson
大家在高中时读了爱默生
so much about individualism and the self
那么多关于个人主义和自我的书
why is it that there's such high levels of conformity?
为什么你们还是那么随波逐流?
Why is it that so many people go on the path
为什么有那么多人还是走
that has been already taken and prescribed by others?
以前很多人已经走过的路?
That doesn't mean that everyone who goes on the path conforms
这并不意味着走这条路的人都是随波逐流的
Again, you can be highly conforming
再一次 你可能很循规蹈矩
choosing to work as a consultant or choosing to be a volunteer
选择做一个顾问或者在流浪者之家
at a homeless shelter
做自愿者
You can be equally other determined or equally self determined
你可能是取决于他人的 也可能是取决于自我的
It's not about choosing a particular path
重点不在于选哪条路
But why did I
重点是为什么
why do we see so many people who conform?
我们会看到这么多随波逐流的人?
And I think it's because of their right raise
我想这是因为他们的成长教育
I think it's because people in the United States
我想是因为美国人
Western world in general
或者普遍来说 西方世界
do not take enough time to reflect
没有花足够的时间来反省
and to think about those questions such as
思考这样的问题:
"what do I reall, really want to do with my life?
"我真正想过的人生是怎样的?"
to ask questions such as
问这样的问题:
"what would I do in a world where no one would know
"在一个没有人知道我在做什么的世界里
what I was doing?"
我会做什么?"
to go through the three question process - the meaning
用三问法来问自己 意义
"what is meaningful?"; "what is pleasurable?"
"什么有意义?" "什么让我快乐?"
"what do I enjoy?"; and "what am I good at?"
"我喜欢什么?" "我擅长什么?"
"What are my strengths?"
"我的强项是什么?"
To go through these questions and to ask
问自己这些问题
those important questions
问这些重要的问题
because when we take a step back and take the time
因为当我们退后一步 慢慢思考
that's when we become ourselve
这时我们才能变成自我
that's when we identify the path that is right for me
我们才能找到适合我们的道路
Let me illustrate this by showing you a stage model
我想用一个阶段模型来给大家讲解
And this is based on the work of Daniel Gilbert
这是以Daniel Gilbert的研究为基础的
indirectly refers to it his work on cognitive dizziness
与他的认知晕眩研究有间接关系
And what he and others have shown is that
他和其他人的研究发现
people behave very differently when they are cognitively busy
当人的认知忙乱时 当他们匆匆忙忙时
when they are in a hurry
他们的行为会非常不同于
versus when they have time
当他们慢慢花时间
they can focus on whatever it is that they are doing
专心思考一下他们所做的事时
So also connected to Tim Kasser's work on time affluence
也跟Tim Kasser的时间充裕研究有关
So the first stage is the stage where we don't have time
第一个段阶是我们没有时间的阶段
we are in a hurry; we are rushed
我们很赶时间 匆匆忙忙
our reaction is automatic
我们的反应是无意识的
This is the part where we conform
在这个阶段 我们会随波逐流
This is time when we conform to the group
我们会遵从群体
as in the Asch experiments
就像Asch做的实验那样
this is when we conform to the man with a white coat
在这个阶段 当那个穿白袍的人
telling us the experiment must go on
告诉我们实验必须继续时 我们会遵从
And we push the button and shock an innocent victim
我们会按下按钮 电击一个无辜的人
This is where conformity to obedience
在这个阶段我们会随波逐流地服从
conformity to a group is
服从群体
when we don't have time
当我们没有时间时
when we are busy
当我们匆忙时
when we don't really think about
当我们不认真思考
what it is that we want to do and can do
我们想做什么 可以做什么时
This is our dependent self - stage one
这是依赖的自我 第一阶段
We very often at this moment can reach stage two
通常这时我们会到达第二阶段
don't need to wait a long time
不用等很久
At this moment, if we take the time
这时 如果我们慢慢来
because when we take the time
因为如果我们慢慢来
that's when we engage in deliberate reflection
这时我们就开始有意识思考
combining reflection and action
把思考与行为结合起来
where we think about what we do
这时候我们会想我们做的事
we think about what we think
想我们想的事
We take our time
我们慢慢来
This is where the self is autonomous
这个阶段的自我是自主的
this is where the independent self-esteem emerges
这时候独立型自尊出现了
when we have the time
当我们慢慢来时
That's where we are much less likely to conform
我们随波逐流的可能性就会减低
that's when we are cultivating
这时我们会培养
and expressing our independent core self
表达我们独立的核心自我
Think of the, of the following experiment
想想接下来的一个实验
It cannot be done today unfortune... Well
今天做不了 很可惜
I mean it's not unfortunate
其实也不可惜
but it cannot be done today
今天做不了
And that is to retry the Milgram experiment with one difference
这个实验其实是重复Milgram的实验 但有一个改动
Imagine this - some of you know the Milgram experiment
大家想象一下 有些同学熟悉Milgram实验
We've spoken about it here
我们在班上已经讲过了
You are sitting on the chair with your hand on the buttons
你坐在椅子里 手放在按钮上
Or in front of you, you have the panel
或者在你面前有一个控制台
And you go up to sixty volts
你选择60伏电压
And there's no real reaction from the other person, the learner
那个学习者没有什么反应
And you go up to 75 volts
你上升到75伏
a 15 volt increment
增加了15伏
And you get to 120 volts and the confederate
你升高到120伏 那个被电击的人
whom you think is really being shocked
你觉得他真的被电击了
says "Ouch! That hurts"
他说"哎哟 很痛"
And you go and you look up at the person with the white coat
你抬起头看那个穿白袍的人
and he says to you "the experiment must go on"
他说"实验必须继续"
And you go up and up; and the person is screaming
你继续提高电压 那个人被电得尖叫
and telling you he has a heart condition
告诉你他要心脏病发了
And you look up at the experimenter
你抬头看实验人员
who looks like this
他看起来就像那样
And he tells you - I never noticed him until now
他告诉你…我之前一直没注意过他
I'm glad I've never noticed him
很高兴我从没注意过他
He says to you "the experiment must go on"
他跟你说"实验必须继续"
And you go on
你继续
And they start to whimper and say
那些人开始大哭起来
"I have a heart condition, Get me out of here!"
"我有心脏病 快放我出去"
And you look up
你抬头看
And the experimenter says
实验人员说
"no answer is wrong answer
"没有答案是错误的答案
Raise the voltage. The experiment must go on."
提高电压 实验必须继续
Now 63 percent of participants went above 350 volt
这时63%的参与者会把电压提高到350伏
which is beyond the level where the person was not even heard anymore
超过那个人所能承受的水平
They continue to shock them until the point of xxx
他们继续电击到 直到XXX点
beyond the very dangerous
超过了危险水平
because he told them that the experiment must go on
因为他告诉他们 实验必须继续
Now imagine the same experiment with a slight difference
现在想象一下 同样的实验 但有一个小小的改动
You give them 75 volts and they say
你用75伏电压电他们 他们说
"Ouch! That hurts"
"哎哟 很痛"
And then the experimenter tells you
然后实验人员告诉你
"The experiment must go on
"实验必须继续
Why don't you come back in 15 minutes"
不如你先休息15分钟"
And you go out for 15 minutes
你出去15分钟
And you come back again
等你回来时
And it's now at 90
这时是90伏
And you go up - let's say - you go up to 120
假设你提高到120伏
And 120, the person is screaming
120伏 那个人在尖叫
"Get me out of here! You have no right to keep me here!"
"放我出去 你们没权把我关在这里"
And you look up at the experimenter and the experimenter says
你抬头看实验人员 他告诉你
"The experiment must go on
"实验必须继续
But why don't you take a 15 minute break?"
不如你先休息15分钟?"
What do you think would happen
你们认为这时会怎么样
if people were given 15 minute breaks between shocks?
如果这些人电击人之前有15分钟的时间休息?
Do you think 63 percent would go to extremely dangerous and beyond?
你认为会有63%的人会把电压提高到超过危险水平吗?
Probably not, because during these 15 minutes
很可能不会 因为在这15分钟里
we are no longer in a hot state
我们不再处于热态
but rather in a cold state
而是处于冷态
the words of George Loewenstein
这是引用George Loewenstein的话
When they are in a cold state, they'll think
当他们处于冷态时 他们会想
"Am I out of my mind? What am I doing here?"
"我疯了吗? 我在这里干什么?"
And they will go and call the police
他们会去打电话报警
as opposed to going back 15 minutes later and
而不是15分钟后再走进去
"Ok, now I'm willing to kill them"
"好的 现在我愿意杀了他们"
which is essentially what they presumably did in that experiment
因为他们在这个实验里就是以为自己杀了这些人
But when they didn't have those 15 minutes
如果他们没有那15分钟
when it was "the experiment must go on"
而是"实验必须继续"
"the experiment must go on"
"实验必须继续"
it went on
他们就会继续
And they paid a price of losing themselves
他们会为失去自我付出代价
And this is what happens to us in modern life
我们的现代生活也是这样
not with such dire consequences
当然后果没有Milgram的实验
potentially could have been with Milgram
那么可怕
and we are not doing immoral things
而且在现代 即使我们服从权威
as the cases with obedience to authority
我们也没做什么不道德的事
But we are hurting ourselves very often
但通常我们会伤害到自己
because we are running around and we are conforming
因为我们随波逐流 遵从主流
and we are doing what they think we should do
我们做别人认为我们该做的事
we are doing what that voice or voices are telling us to do
我们做那把声音叫我们做的事
We are not doing what we are meant to be doing
我们没有做自己想做的事
You know what I think the most important part of this class?
你们知道我认为这门课最重要的部分是什么吗?
Its sections and response papers
是课堂和课后作业
This is not out of modesty
我这么说不是因为谦虚
yes, I want you to think that I'm modest
没错 我想你们觉得我谦虚
but that's not why I'm
但这不是我
why I'm saying it
这么说的原因
It's because that is when you get the time to reflect
而是因为这时候你们有时间思考
to talk about it with your teaching fellows
和你们的助教讨论
with your fellow students
和你们的同学讨论
to think about it
思考
You are "forced" to take a timeout
你们被迫用额外时间来思考
It's when you sit down and write those response papers
这时你们坐下写课后作业
about these questions that I mentioned
回答我提出的问题
it's when your real autonomous shining self comes ou
这时你们真正的独立自我浮现了
it's when you talk to your friends about this class
这时你跟朋友谈这门课
or your block mates in the dining hall
或者在食堂跟队友分享
when you take the time to share with your parents
这时你有时间和你的父母分享
That's when it is happening
这是独立自我就出现了
Finally, integrity
最后 正直
Nathaniel Branden
Nathaniel Branden did this with many of his clients - he's a therapist
Nathaniel Branden和他的很多病人这样做过 他是心理治疗师
where he would bring them in and tell them
他叫病人来 告诉他们
"Ok, for the next week, stop
"好的 下周 暂停
No lies, Be fully integrated; be fully honest"
不能说谎 要完全诚实坦白"
And what he found was when he applies to especially people
他发现这个方法 尤其是对于那些
who would lie a little bit more
会撒一点谎的病人来说
that enhanced their self esteem
能够提高他们的自尊
I remember back in 1996 - I think it was 96 or 97
我记得在1996年 96或97年
when the whole Clinton impeachment trial was going on
克林顿弹劾案正在审判
On CNN they brought on DePaulo
CNN请来DePaulo
she is a professor at University of Virginia
她是维珍尼亚大学的一位教授
and she does research on lying
她专门研究说谎
And they interviewed her and it was the first time
他们采访了她 那是第一次
that I was exposed to her work
我接触到她的研究
And she said on CNN that her research shows that
她在CNN上说她的研究发现
basically everyone lies - many times little lies
基本上所有人都说谎 很多时候都是一些小谎
intended to impress others
为了让别人觉得自己很厉害
many times, bigger lies
很多时候是大谎
And what she found was that
她发现
people lie in average 3 times a day
人平均每天说三个谎
And when I heard it
当我听到的时候
I scoffed, I said
我轻笑了一声
"Wel, maybe other people lie three times a day
"也许其他人每天说三次谎
I don't lie"
但我不说谎"
And let me explain to you why I don't lie
我解释一下为什么说我不撒谎
And this is true
这是真的
Because I wrote my senior thesis in college
因为我读大学时写的毕业论文
on the concept of honesty pays
就是说诚实是会带来好处的
I was a joint philosophy and psychology concentrator
我当时既学心理也学哲学
was interested in ethics, self esteem, motivation
我对道德 自尊 动机感兴趣
And what I showed based on research
我根据研究
based on philosophical works by Aristotle, by Adam Smith
根据亚里士多德 亚当・史密斯的哲学著作
that we pay a high psychological and emotional price whenever we lie
发现每次我们说谎 欺骗 不诚实时
whenever we cheat
要付出巨大的
whenever we are dishonest
心理和情绪代价
And then I said to myself
所以我跟自己说
"But let me try DePaulo's exercise."
"让我试试DePaulo的方法"
What she does is have people evaluate their conversations
她的方法就是叫人讲完一段对话后
for honest or dishonest content right after it finishes
马上评估有哪些是真的 有哪些是说谎的
so when it's still fresh in their mind
趁他们还清楚记得
what they talked about
自己说过什么
So they keep a journal
他们会写一本日记
which is completely anonymous
完全匿名的
So I said
所以我想
"But I'm gonna do , even though I don't lie"
"我会写 虽然我不说谎"
because I know the consequences of lying
因为我知道说谎的后果
because I wrote my thesis on it
因为我的论文就是写这个的
I'm an expert on honesty
我是诚实这个课题的专家
I said I'll still do it
我说我会写日记的
Cause I like to try experiments
因为我想实验一下
As it happens
就在我写日记的期间
I went on a date that night
有一天晚上我出去约会
someone whom I never met before - was not Arianna
一个我没见过的人 不是Arianna
someone that was whom my mom set me up with
是我妈妈给我介绍的
My mom and her mom talked together in the same school
我妈和她妈说我们在同一间学校
And I heard wonderful things about her
然后我听说了她的一些很棒的事迹
I was very excited
我很激动
and became even more excited when we met
我们见了面以后就更加激动了
And we were sitting down and having a lovely dinner and talking
我们坐下来 吃饭聊天 很愉快
And she is an economist
她是一个经济学家
very successful economist
非常成功的经济学家
And she asked me what I was doing
她问我是做什么的
and I told her that I was a psychologist
我告诉她我是心理学家
And I was really impressing her with all my knowledge of psychology
我用我全部的心理知识在她面前表现自己
And she said:"You know I'm also interested in psychology."
她说"我也对心理学感兴趣"
And I said:"This is going really well"
我说"这一定会很顺利"
To myself, not to her
我自己心里说的 不是跟她说
I learned not to say those things on earlier dates
我学到了教训 刚开始约会时不要说这样的话
So we were sitting down and - you know
我们坐下来…
learn to fail
要学会失败
So we were sitting down and talking
我们坐下来聊天
Then she said
然后她说
"Oh, you know,I just read about the psychologist"
"我刚读到一个心理学家的著作"
And she said the name
她说了这个人的名字
you know, it's a very famous psychologis
非常著名的一个心理学家
"You know him,right?"
"你听说过他吧?"
Now I didn't have the faintest clue who was she
我完全不知道
who she was talking about - no idea
她说的是谁 完全不知道
And I remember pausing for a second
我记得我呆了一下
and looking at her and just smiling
微笑地看着她
"Hmm, mHmmm"
"嗯嗯"
And the conversation continued to flow
然后我们继续聊
Now I would not have noticed this
我没有注意到自己说谎了
except for the fact that afterwards I went home
但后来我回到家
and went over the conversation
回想这次的对话
Then I said "Hey wait a minut, I just lied to her!"
我说"慢着 我刚才跟她说谎了"
And ever since then
从那时起
I've been doing this regularly - lying that is
我就经常这么做 我指的是说谎
No, I've been doing this regularly
不 我经常这么做
Ever since then
从那时起
I've been keeping doing the integrity exercise
我就坚持磨练自己的正直
that DePaulo talks about
用DePaulo说的方法
that Nathaniel Branden talks about
用Nathaniel Branden说的方法
to be very conscious about my conversations
非常留意我说的话
Am I just saying things to impress
我这么说是为了表现自己
which are not authentic?
而说的假话吗?
Am I having those little lies?
我是不是说了小谎?
Because you see, when we are telling the truth
因为你们要明白 当我们说实话时
the message that we communicate to ourselves
我们给自己传达了一个信息
我们给自己传达的信息是
is that my words are worthy
我的话是有价值的
my words are important; I matter
我的话很重要 我很重要
And when we don't do that
当我们不说实话时
when we tell lies
当我们说谎时
or we are about impressing constantly
或者我们想不停地表现自己时
we are saying "I'm not good enough as I am."
我们是在说"这样的我不够好"
I need to be someone else so that the other person likes
我需要成为另一个人 让别人来喜欢我
I need to know that psychologist
我需要知道这个心理学家
because otherwise she won't like me
不然她就不会喜欢我
instead of being authentic and real
而不是做真实的自己
instead of being known rather than validated
选择被认同而不是被了解
and doing it and being conscious of it for a week  at a time
用这个方法坚持一周
until the behavior changes our attitude
直到行为改变了我们的态度
and I begin to value my words much more
我开始更重视我的话
when I communicate myself - who I am
当我跟自己传达 我是谁
rather than trying to impress others
而不是想着让别人觉得自己很厉害时
When I assert myself
当我肯定自己时
when I say no at times
当我时不时地说"不"时
so that I can simplify my life a little bit
这样我就能简化我的生活
when I say yes when it's appropriate
当我该说是的时候说是
even it's not the most popular yes in the world
即使这个"是"不是很受欢迎
but it's right for me
但我应该这样说
And it's about expanding it in time as well as in space
还要从时间和空间上把这个方法扩展开来
It is started first of all by myself
首先从我自己开始
why does journaling help so much?
为什么写日记这么有用?
Why does therapy with an empathic therapist
为什么有移情心的治疗师
why does it work so well?
他们的治疗这么有效?
Because we are ourselves
因为我们活出了自我
we don't try impress the therapist
我们没有想着在治疗师面前表现自己
After a while we open up
一段时间后 我们打开心扉
We don't try to impress our journal
我们没有想着在日记里表现自己
We are ourselves
我们活出了自我
And expanding it from our journal which makes us feel good
从让我们感觉良好的日记扩展到
to close relationships, to others
亲近的关系和人
from doing it one day one conversation at a time
从一天一次对话中练习正直
to a week of integrity treatment so to speak to lifelong
到坚持一周 然后坚持一生
Imagine leading this life
想象一下 过这样的生活
how freed up do we feel when you no longer need to express
当你不用再不停地表达或表现自己时
or impress ourselves constantly
我们会感到多自由
where we can just be known
我们能够被了解
where we can just be ourselves
能够活出自我
how much lighter
这样会多轻松
how much more power
多有力量
how much more integrity and authenticity we will experience
我们会觉得多正直和真实
how much happier will we be?
我们会多快乐?
I want to end by reading you an excerpt from Melissa Christino's journal
我想在下课前读一段Melissa Christino的日记
which she cited in her senior thesis
是她在她的毕业论文中引用的
This, of course is with her permission
当然这是得到她允许的
Melissa Christino was an undergraduate here, class of 2002
Melissa Christino是哈佛本科毕业生 2002届
And this is what she writes
她是这样写的
"Your true potential lies way
"你真正的潜力
way down in the depths of your soul...
埋藏在你的灵魂深处
in the pit of your stomach
在你腹部最底处
past your knowledge, beyond your nervousness
在你的知识和紧张触及不到的地方
and buried under your fears and anxieties
埋藏在你的恐惧和焦虑之下
As hidden as it may be
虽然它隐藏起来了
it is still there
但它还在那里
I know it's there because I've felt it before
我知道 因为我以前感受过它的存在
and I know it's there in others too
我知道别人也有
because I've seen others perform miracles
因为我见过别人做过奇迹一般的事
There is a faint glow of unparalleled potential in all of us
我们体内都有一股无可匹敌的潜力 散发着微弱的光芒
and when we find it ― it shine."
当我们找到它时 它就会发出万丈光芒"
It's there in each and every one of us - this glow
我们每个人都有这丝微光
And if we feed it, if we cultivate it, it grows
如果我们助长它 培养它 它就会壮大
And it grows to the level that expands beyond the self
它就会壮大到超越自己
where people like Warren Bennis
这时候 像Warren Bennis这样的人
where people like Nelson Mandela
像曼德拉这样的人
where people like Anita Roddick
像Anita Roddick这样的人
people like mother Teresa - just their presence
像特蕾莎修女这样的人 他们的存在
just their presence, their being shines a light onto others
他们的存在 就能为别人散发光芒
So what I'd like you to do now
现在我想这样做
we have 4 more minute
只剩四分钟
here's what I'd like to do now
我想这样做
I'm going to play a song for yo
我会放一首歌给大家听
usually played at the beginning
通常我会在上课前放的
I want to play it at the end today
但今天我想在最后才放
If you feel comfortable
如果你们喜欢的话
you can close your eyes and listen to the words of the song
可以闭上眼睛 听歌词
and what they mean to you
它们对你有什么意义
what they mean in the context of your life
对你的生活有什么意义
So if you feel comfortable
所以如果你们喜欢
close your eyes, and listen
闭上眼睛听
really listen to the following words
听听以下的歌词
[SONG: Gloria Gaynor "I Am What I Am"]
I am what I am
我就是我
I am my own special creation
我独一无二
So come take a look
看我一眼
Give me the hook
对我嗤之以鼻
Or the ovation
或为我鼓掌
It's my world
这是我的世界
That I want to have a little pride in
我想拥有一点骄傲
My world
我的世界
And it's not a place I have to hide in
在这里我不用躲藏
Life's not worth a damn
生命毫无价值
Till you can say
直到你能说
I am what I am
我就是我
Open your eyes!
睁开眼睛
C'mon! Get up
来吧 上来
I am what I am
我就是我
All right. Let's go down
好的 我们下去
Let's join them
和他们一起跳